{
  "categories": {
    "Worship": {
      "Tawheed and Shirk": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "What is the greatest worship?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "the prayer",
            "Zakat",
            "unification. -- Tawheed",
            "charity"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "unification. -- Tawheed",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "What is the ruling on turning away from the religion of Allah, the Almighty, in knowledge and practice?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "ignorant",
            "KUFR because he committed a nullifier of Islam",
            "a stubborn hypocrite",
            "wrongdoer"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "KUFR because he committed a nullifier of Islam",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "At-Taghut is inclusive of all that is worshipped other than Allah true or false.",
          "question_type": "True Or False",
          "answers": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "True",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "The following nullifies one's Tawheed except.",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Whoever mocks something from the din of the Messenger or the rewards of Allah or His punishment",
            "Whoever places between him and Allah intermediaries",
            "Aiding and supporting the mushrikin against the Muslimin",
            "Whoever Prays without Wudū'"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Whoever Prays without Wudū",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "Tawheed has ____ number of conditions",
          "question_type": "fill-in-the-blanks",
          "answers": [
            "5",
            "7",
            "10",
            "2"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "7",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "Which one of the folowing in not a condition of Tawheed?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Al-i’lm (Knowledge)",
            "Al-Mahabba (Love)",
            "Al-Yaqeen (Certainty)",
            "As-Sidq (Truthfulness)",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "None of the above",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "There are only Two Pillars of Tawheed true of false",
          "question_type": "True Or False",
          "answers": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "True",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "The Tawaghit are many and their heads are five except?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "The oppressive ruler who changes the laws of Allah(swt)",
            "The one who claims knowledge of the unseen",
            "The one who is worshipped and pleased with it",
            "The one who does not govern by what Allah(swt) has revealed",
            "Satan who invites people to worship other than Allah (swt)",
            "Jesus, peace be upon him"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Jesus, peace be upon him",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "The following are steps required in rejection of Taghut, which one is not?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "To show Hatred",
            "Avoid worshipping Taghut",
            "Al-i'lm (Knowledge)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Al-i'lm (knowledge)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "To be a monotheist, one should know divine rights of Allah(swt). Which of the following is not?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "All the acts that are specific to Allah(swt) alone which no-one should ascribe to other than Allah(swt)",
            "All the powers of Allah(swt) that controls the entire universe",
            "All the acts of worship that should be directed to Him Alone",
            "All the names and attributes,which no one should ascribe to other than Allah(swt)",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "None of the above",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "The following nullifies one's Tawheed except",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Whoever mocks something from the din of the Messenger or the rewards of Allah or His punishment",
            "Whoever places between him and Allah intermediaries",
            "Aiding and supporting the mushrikin against the Muslimin",
            "Whoever Prays without Wudū'"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Whoever Prays without Wudū'",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ],
      "Names of Allah": [
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "Fasting is one of the pillars",
          "question_type": "fill-in-the-blanks",
          "answers": [
            "Islam",
            "Faith",
            "charity",
            "Taqwah"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Islam",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "ما هي الارض المباركة",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "الشام",
            "افريقيا",
            "اوروبا"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "الشام",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ]
    },
    "The Qur'an": {
      "Prophets & Messengers": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "Who is the prophet who is mentioned the most in the Qur'an?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Jesus, peace be upon him",
            "Abraham, peace be upon him",
            "Moses, peace be upon him",
            "Muhammad, peace and blessings be upon him"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Moses, peace be upon him",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "What is the name of the surah that you read equals one-third of the Qur’an?",
          "question_type": "fill-in-the-blanks",
          "answers": [
            "Surah Al-Mulk",
            "Suratul Yaseen",
            "Surah Al-Falaq",
            "Surah Al-Ikhlas"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sura Al-Ikhlas",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "who is the prophet who was given Taurat?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Muhammad, peace and blessings be upon him",
            "Jesus, peace be upon him",
            "Moses, peace be upon him",
            "Abraham, peace be upon him"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Moses, peace be upon him",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ],
      "Books of Allah": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "What is the surah in which the basmalah was mentioned twice?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Surah Al-Mulk",
            "Surah Maryam",
            "Surat Al-Naml",
            "Surat Al-Shuara"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Surat Al-Naml",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "In which surah is the story of Taloot and Goliath mentioned?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "The Norms",
            "The Table",
            "The Cow",
            "The Poets"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The Cow",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "The last bow (Sajdah) of the Holy Qur’ān is in which Sūrah? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Surah an-Najm (The Star)",
            "Surah al-Inshiqaq (The Splitting)",
            "Surah al-'Alaq (The Clinging Substance)",
            "Suurah as-Sajdah (The Prostration)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Surah al-Inshiqaq (The Splitting)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "How many Sūrah’s name is only one letter? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Three",
            "Two",
            "Five",
            "Four"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Three",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "How many Sūrah of the Qur’ān Start with Al-Hamdulillah (الحمد لله) ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Three",
            "Six",
            "Seven",
            "Four"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Four",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "Mention the names of the Books of Allah",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "1.Taurat   2.Kutubu 3.Injeel   4.The Qur’an",
            "1.Taurat   2.Zaboor 3.Lah      4.The Qur’an",
            "1.Taurat   2.Zaboor 3.Injeel   4.The Qur’ān",
            "1.Taurat   2.Zaboor 3.Injeel   4.Kitab"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "1.Taurat   2.Zaboor 3.Injeel   4.The Qur’ān",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "What is the name of Prophet to whom Taurat was revealed?  ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Prophet Musa",
            "Prophet Isa",
            "Prophet Daud",
            "Prophet Ibrahim"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Prophet Musa",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "What is the name of Prophet to whom Zaboor was revealed? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Prophet Musa",
            "Prophet Isa",
            "Prophet Daud",
            "Prophet Ibrahim"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Prophet Daud",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "What is the name of Prophet to whom Injeel was revealed? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Prophet Musa",
            "Prophet Isa",
            "Prophet Daud",
            "Prophet Ibrahim"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Prophet Isa",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "In which Sūrah Bismillah Ar-Rahmaneen Ar-Raheem (بسم الله الرحمن الرحيم) came twice? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Surah an-Naml (The Ant)",
            "Surah al-Inshiqaq (The Splitting)",
            "Surah al-'Alaq (The Clinging Substance",
            "Suurah as-Sajdah (The Prostration)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Surah an-Naml (The Ant)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "What is the name of cave where revelation of Holy Qur’an started?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "The Cave of Burūj",
            "The Cave of Judah",
            "The Cave of Kahf",
            "The Cave of Hira"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The Cave of Hira",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "According to Sūrah Al-'Asr, Most man is surely in loss, except those: ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "They who are during their prayer humbly submissive",
            "Who pray five time a day",
            "They who carefully maintain their prayers",
            "Who have believed and done righteous deeds and advised each other to truth and advised each other to patience."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Who have believed and done righteous deeds and advised each other to truth and advised each other to patience.",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": " Which Sūrah is on the name of one metal? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Sūrah Al-Qamar",
            "Sūrah Al-Hadeed",
            "Sūrah Al-An’ām",
            "Sūrah Al-Ahqāf"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sūrah Al-Hadeed",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": " In which Sūrah the name of Allah is repeated in every verse",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Sūrah Al-Mujādilah",
            "Sūrah Ar-Rahmān",
            "Sūrah Al-Hajj",
            "Sūrah Al-Layl"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sūrah Al-Mujādilah",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": " How many total Sūrahs of the Holy Qur’ān start with the word Ha-meem (حٰم)? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Eight",
            "Six",
            "Seven",
            "Four"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Six",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "question": " The story of the worship of cow of Bani Israeel mentioned in which Sūrah? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Sūrah An-Nahl",
            "Sūrah Al-Baqarah",
            "Sūrah An-Naml",
            "Sūrah Al-An’ām"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sūrah Al-Baqarah",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "question": "How many Sūrahs of the Holy Qur’ān start with the word Alif-laam-Raa (الر)? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "2 Sūrahs",
            "4 Sūrahs",
            "5 Sūrahs",
            "3 Sūrahs"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "4 Sūrahs",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "question": "Who has Allah mentioned in the Qur’ān as the best example to follow? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Prophet Muhammad (ﷺ)",
            "Prophet (Isa) Jesus (عليه السالم)",
            "Prophet (Musa) Moses (عليه السالم)",
            "Angels"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Prophet Muhammad (ﷺ)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 19,
          "question": "In which Sura the law of inheritance mentioned? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Surah an-Nisaa",
            "Surah al-Inshiqaq (The Splitting)",
            "Surah al-'Alaq (The Clinging Substance",
            "Suurah as-Sajdah (The Prostration)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Surah an-Nisaa",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 20,
          "question": "In which Sūrah of the Holly Qur’ān, Allah mentioned about Khidr? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Sūrah Al-Kahf (The Cave)",
            "Sūrah Al-Qalam (The Pen)",
            "Sūrah Al-Mu’minūn (The Believers)",
            "Sūrah Az-Zumar (The Groups)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sūrah Al-Kahf (The Cave)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 21,
          "question": "In which Sūrah the story of ‘The Sleepers of the Cave’ is mentioned? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Sūrah Al-Kahf (The Cave)",
            "Sūrah Al-Qalam (The Pen)",
            "Sūrah Al-Mu’minūn (The Believers)",
            "Sūrah Az-Zumar (The Groups)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sūrah Al-Kahf (The Cave)",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ]
    },
    "Marriage": {
      "Worship": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "Who are mentioned as garments for one another in the Qur’ān?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Friends",
            "Brothers",
            "Relatives",
            "Spouses"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Spouses",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "How should one treat and live with his wife, according to the Qur’ān? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "A man should treat his wife like a slave",
            "A man should treat his wife like a stranger",
            "A man should treat his wife with kindness and to live in equity",
            "I dunno"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "A man should treat his wife with kindness and to live in equity",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "Is polygamy compulsory in Islām?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Polygamy is general",
            "Polygamy is not a compulsion in Islām - it is an exception",
            "Polygamy is not permitted in Islām",
            "Polygamy is compulsory in Islām"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Polygamy is not a compulsion in Islām - it is an exception",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "What did the prophet(ﷺ) mention about getting married? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Marriage will bring good luck",
            "Marriage completes half of the religious obligations",
            "Marriage is a bad omen",
            "I dunno"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Marriage completes half of the religious obligations",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "Whom did Prophet Muhammad (ﷺ) mention as the best of men? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "The best men are those who do not marry",
            "The best men are those who have more wives",
            "None of the men are considered best",
            "The best among the men are those who are best to their wife"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The best among the men are those who are best to their wife",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "Is the marriage contract valid if a woman was on her menses?",
          "question_type": "Yes or No",
          "answers": [
            "Yes",
            "No"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Yes",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ]
    },
    "Prayer(Swalaah)": {
      "Worship": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": " How many times a day we need to perform obligatory prayers? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Twice",
            "Thrice",
            "4 times",
            "5 times"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "5 times",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "What is Adhan ? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "A chapter in the Quran",
            "Special Ayah",
            "Call for Prayer",
            "islamic poem"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Call for Prayer",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "What do Muslims do to attain a state of purity before offering Salah (prayers)? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Recieting Attahyaatu",
            "Performing Adhan",
            "Performing Udhu",
            "Bathing"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Performing Udhu",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "When praying Witr in the three Rak'a's in the last Rak'ah it is Sunnah to recite? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Sūrah Al-A’lā (The Most High)",
            "Sūrah Al-Ikhlās (The Sincerity), Sūrah  Al-Falaq (The Daybreak), Sūrah  An-Nās (Mankind)",
            "Sūrah Al-Ikhlās (The Sincerity)",
            "Sūrah Al-Fātihah (The Opening)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sūrah Al-Ikhlās (The Sincerity)",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ]
    },
    "Charity": {
      "Worship": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "What is the percentage of Obligatory Charity (Zakat) on Muslim?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "3.5%",
            "1.5%",
            "2.5%",
            "4.5%"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "2.5%",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ]
    },
    "Fast(Sawm)": {
      "Worship": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "In which Sūrah of the Holy Qur’ān Fasting of the month of Ramadan is enjoined ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Sūrah  Yūsuf (Joseph)",
            "Sūrah  Al-Baqarah (The Cow)",
            "Sūrah  Yā Seen (Ya Seen)",
            "Sūrah  An-Nisā’ (The Women)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sūrah  Al-Baqarah (The Cow)",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ]
    },
    "Hajj(Pilgrimage)": {
      "Worship": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "For whom Hajj is compulsory ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "The rich",
            "The Poor",
            "Both Poor & Poor",
            "Every Muslim"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The rich",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "Hajj is not completed unless you go to? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Makkah",
            "Madina",
            "Mina",
            "Arafat"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Arafat",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "Muzdalifa is situated between",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Mina and Kaaba",
            "Safa and Mina",
            "Mina and Arafat",
            "Makkah and Madina"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Mina and Arafat",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "When Hajj was made compulsory? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "6 A.H",
            "7 A.H",
            "8 A.H",
            "9 A.H"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "7 A.H",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "Which direction is the Tawaf around the Ka'ba made?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Keep Ka'ba on your left and Walk around. (Anti Clockwise)",
            "Keep Ka'ba at the centre while Walking around. (ClockTwise)",
            "Keep Ka'ba on your right and Walk around. (Clockwise)",
            "Not sure"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Keep Ka'ba on your left and Walk around. (Anti Clockwise)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "What is the name of the place where the pilgrims pelt stones on pillars representing the devil?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Al-Jamarat",
            "Mina",
            "Muzdalifa",
            "Al-Ka'abah"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Al-Jamarat",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "What is considered to be the most important part of the Hajj?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "The day the pilgrims spend praying on the Plains of Arafah",
            "Days spent in Mina and Muzdalifah",
            "When pilgrims circumambulate the Kaabah",
            "When pilgrims stone the Pillars representing the devil"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The day the pilgrims spend praying on the Plains of Arafah",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "What is the state of purity in which all pilgrims enter Makkah for Hajj called? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Istighfar",
            "Istikhara",
            "Adhaan",
            "Ihram"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Ihram",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "What does the running or swift walking of pilgrims seven times between the hills of Safaa and Marwah represent? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "The number of times the Prophet Muhammad performed the Hajj in his lifetime",
            "The number of times the Prophet Abraham (عليه السالم) tried to build the Kaabah before he succeeded",
            "The number of miles the Prophet Muhammad travelled from Medina to Mecca to perform the Hajj",
            "The number of times Hajar ran back and forth between the hills searching for water for her son Ismai(عليه السالم)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The number of times Hajar ran back and forth between the hills searching for water for her son Ismai(عليه السالم)",
          "month": "Dhul"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "The best Dua to say in the day of Arafah is________",
          "question_type": "fill-in-the-blanks",
          "answers": [
            "Subhaanaallahi",
            "La illaha-Allah wa dahu la shareeka lahu, lahu mulku wa lahu hamdu wa huwa, ala kuli shayin qadeer",
            "La haw la wa laa quwwatta illaa billahi",
            "Alhamdulillah"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "La illaha-Allah wa dahu la shareeka lahu, lahu mulku wa lahu hamdu wa huwa, ala kuli shayin qadeer",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "Sa'i (Walking back and forth between Safa and Marwa) is an important part of Hajj and Umrah.  The act of worship was inspired by the action of",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Haajar (عليه السالم)",
            "Ismaeel (عليه السالم)",
            "Muhammad (ﷺ)",
            "Ibrahim (عليه السالم)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Haajar (عليه السالم)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "How many times do the Muslims circumambulate (Tawaf) the Kaabah? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Seven Times only",
            "Ten Times to make it complete",
            "Three Times only",
            "Five Times only"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Seven Times only",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "Seven Times only",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Pilgrimage to Shrines",
            "Pilgrimage to Monasteries",
            "Pilgrimage to Makkah",
            "Pilgrimage to Iran"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Pilgrimage to Makkah",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "When praying Witr in the three Rak'a's in the last Rak'ah it is Sunnah to recite? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Every year",
            "Once in five years",
            "At least Once in their lifetime",
            "Once in a decade"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "At least Once in their lifetime",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "What do Muslims recite during and throughout the Hajj? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Al-Fatiha",
            "Taalbiya",
            "Declaration of Hajj",
            "There is no specific recitation"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Taalbiya",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ]
    },
    "History": {
      "Basic Knowladge": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "What is the name of year when our Beloved Prophet (ﷺ) was born? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "The Year of the Cow (Al-Baqarah)",
            "The Year of the Ant (An-Naml)",
            "The Year of the Elephant (Al-Fīl)",
            "The Year of the Goat (Al-Kharuf)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The Year of the Elephant (Al-Fīl)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "How many Eid Celebrations are there in Islām?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Islāmic New year, Eid Al-Fitr and Adha",
            "Eid Al-Fitr, Adha, Maulud and Islāmic New year",
            "Eid of Fitr and Adha",
            "Parent's Day and Other Day's celebration"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Eid of Fitr and Adha",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "Who took care of our Holy Prophet after his grandfather Abdul Muttalib passed away?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Hamza",
            "Abubakar Siddiq",
            "Khadijah",
            "Abu Talib"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Abu Talib",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "How many sons of our Holy Prophet (ﷺ)? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Three",
            "Six",
            "Two",
            "Four"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Three",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "How many daughters of our Holy Prophet (ﷺ)?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Three",
            "Six",
            "Two",
            "Four"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Four",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "Which member of our Holy Prophet’s family passed away very soon after him?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Zainab",
            "Umm Kulthoom",
            "Fatimah",
            "Rukayyay"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Zainab",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "Give the names of his two blessed Grandsons of our Holy Prophet Muhammad (ﷺ)? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Husna and Husain, (رضي الله عنهما)",
            "Hasan and Husarah, (رضي الله عنهما)",
            "Hasanat and Husainat, (رضي الله عنهما)",
            "Hasan and Husain, (رضي الله عنهما)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Hasan and Husain, (رضي الله عنهما)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "What is the name of first Battle of Islam? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Battle of Uhad",
            "Battle of Ahzāb",
            "Battle of Qadsiyyah",
            "Battle of Badr"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Battle of Badr",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "Which battle gave muslims decisive win in war with byzantine emperor?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Battle of Yarmuk",
            "Battle of Badr",
            "Battle of Khaybar",
            "Battle of Khandak"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Battle of Yarmuk",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "Who is the first martyr (Shaheed) in Islam? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Hamza (رضي الله عنه)",
            "Fatimah (رضي الله عنها)",
            "Sumayyah (رضي الله عنها)",
            "Yasir (رضي الله عنه)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Sumayyah (رضي الله عنها)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "The Sulhu Al hudeybia was written after which battle?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Battle of Uhud",
            "Battle of Ahzāb",
            "Battle of Badr",
            "Battle of Qadsiyyah"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Battle of Uhud",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "Who is the first child accepted Islam? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Hassan, Hussain (رضي الله عنهما)",
            "Ali bin Abi Talib (رضي الله عنه)",
            "Abdullah bin Abbas (رضي الله عنه)",
            "Albdullah bin Umar (رضي الله عنه)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Ali bin Abi Talib (رضي الله عنه)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "Who is the first man accepted Islam?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Abu Bakr As-Siddiq(رضي الله عنه)",
            "Ali Al-Murtaza(رضي الله عنه)",
            "Uthman bin Affan (رضي الله عنه)",
            "Umar Al-Farooq(رضي الله عنه)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Abu Bakr As-Siddiq(رضي الله عنه)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "What are the names of the four Khulafa-e-Rashideen (رضي الله عنهم)?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Abdullahi bin Abass, - Umar Al-Faruq, - Uthman, - Ali",
            "Abu-Bakr As-Siddiq, - Umar Al-Faruq bin Khattab, - Uthman bin Affan, - Ali bin Abi Talib",
            "Abu-Bakr As-Siddiq, - Umar Al-Faruq, - Amar bin Yaris, - Ali",
            "Abu-Bakr As-Siddiq, - Umar Al-Faruq, - Usman, - Ali"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Abu-Bakr As-Siddiq, - Umar Al-Faruq bin Khattab, - Uthman bin Affan, - Ali bin Abi Talib",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "Our beloved Prophet (ﷺ) went on a miraculous night journey to Masjid al-Aqsa and to the Heavens. What is this journey called? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Masabaq",
            "Isrā’ and Mi’raj",
            "Hijrah",
            "Mi’raj"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Isrā’ and Mi’raj",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "question": "What are the names of the two Khulafa-e-Rashideen (رضي الله عنهم) a whose daughters married to the Prophet Muhammad (ﷺ)?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Abu-Bakr As-Siddiq and Ali bin Abi Talib (رضي الله عنهما)",
            "Uthman bin Affan and Umar al-Farooq (رضي الله عنهما)",
            "Abu-Bakr As-Siddiq and Umar al-Farooq (رضي الله عنهما)",
            "Uthman bin Affan and Ali bin Abi Talib (رضي الله عنهما)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Uthman bin Affan and Ali bin Abi Talib (رضي الله عنهما)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "question": "What gift did he bring back from Allah from the miraculous night journey to the heavens? ",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Al-Qur’ān",
            "Goodies",
            "Hadith",
            "Five times daily salah"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Five times daily salah",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "question": " Which was the first capital of Islamic State",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Makkah",
            "Taaif",
            "Jiddah",
            "Madina"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Madina",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 19,
          "question": "What companion of Prophet Muhammad(ﷺ) was awarded with the title of \"The sword of Allah\"?",
          "question_type": "multiple-choice",
          "answers": [
            "Abu Bakr As-Siddiq(رضي الله عنه)",
            "Ali Al-Murtaza(رضي الله عنه)",
            "Khalid bin Waleed(رضي الله عنه)",
            "Umar Al-Farooq(رضي الله عنه)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Khalid bin Waleed(رضي الله عنه)",
          "month": "null"
        },
        {
          "id": 20,
          "question": "Prophet Muhammad (ﷺ) belonged to _____ family?",
          "question_type": "fill-in-the-blanks",
          "answers": [
            "Quraishi",
            "Makki",
            "Hashmi",
            "Madni"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Hashmi",
          "month": "null"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
}